They come in pieces.
The Lego Movie 2: The Second Part is a action, adventure,
animation film directed by Mike Mitchell.
It's been five years since everything was awesome and the citizens are facing a huge new threat: LEGO
DUPLO® invaders from outer space, wrecking everything faster than they can rebuild.
Emmet Brickowski / Rex Dangervest (voice), played by Chris Pratt.
Wyldstyle / Lucy (voice), played by Elizabeth Banks.
Batman (voice), played by Will Arnett.
Queen Watevra Wa'Nabi (voice), played by Tiffany Haddish.
General Mayhem / Sweet Mayhem (voice), played by Stephanie Beatriz.
Unikitty / Ultrakatty (voice), played by Alison Brie.
The Lego Movie 2: The Second Part is a 2019 animated adventure comedy film directed
by Mike Mitchell and written by Phil Lord and Christopher Miller.
Based on the Lego construction toys, it is the fourth
in the The Lego Movie film series.
Chris Pratt, Elizabeth Banks, Will Arnett, Charlie Day, Alison Brie and Nick Offerman reprise their roles
from the first film, with Tiffany Haddish, Stephanie Beatriz and Maya Rudolph joining the cast.
The film takes place five years after the events of the previous film and follows Emmet Brickowski, Lucy and their friends, who travel into
the Systar System to test their skills and creativity, while Emmet deals with a coming cataclysm known as "Armamageddon".
Development of a sequel to The Lego Movie began in February 2014.
In March, it was announced that the film would be directed by Chris McKay and in October
it was reported that Lord and Miller would return as the screenwriters.
In February 2015, McKay was replaced as director by Rob Schrab, who in turn was replaced
in February 2017 by Mike Mitchell, reportedly due to creative differences.
Production for the film began in October 2017, with the majority of the cast
returning to voice the characters in mid-2018, along with the new cast.
As with the previous films in the franchise, the
animation was provided by Animal Logic.
Mark Mothersbaugh, who composed The Lego Movie and The Lego Ninjago Movie, returned to compose the film's musical score, with
artists including Dillon Francis, Beck, Robyn and The Lonely Island providing original songs for the film.
The Lego Movie 2: The Second Part premiered in Los Angeles on February 2, 2019,
and was released in the United States on February 8 by Warner Bros.
It received generally positive reviews from critics, although
it was considered inferior to its predecessor.
Despite grossing $199.6 million against a budget of $99 million, the film became the
franchise's second box office disappointment after The Lego Ninjago Movie.
The film explores themes of villain, time travel, sequel,
based on toy, live action and animation.
The tone is lighthearted.